boden.com 2019-12-20

# Privacy Notice | Boden US

Under California law, customers of Bodenusa.com who are residents of California have certain rights regarding their personal information. This section describes the rights of California residents under the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) and how to exercise them.

**_Your rights_**

You have the right to request that we disclose certain information to you about our collection and use of your personal information over the past 12 months. Once we receive and verify your request, we will disclose to you:

  * The categories of personal information we collected about you.
  * The categories of sources from which the personal information is collected.
  * The specific pieces of personal information we collected about you.
  * Our business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling any personal information.
  * The purposes for which the information we collected will be used.
  * The categories of third parties with whom we share personal information.
  * If we sold or disclosed your personal information for a business purpose; and, if so, any categories of personal information that were sold or disclosed, and the categories of any third parties to whom personal information was sold or disclosed.

You have the right to request that we delete any of your personal information that we collected from you and retained, subject to certain exceptions. Once we receive and verify your request, we will delete (and direct our service providers to delete) your personal information from our records, unless an exception applies.

We may deny your deletion request if retaining the information is necessary for us or our service providers to:

  * Complete the transaction for which we collected the personal information, provide a good or service that you requested, take actions reasonably anticipated within the context of our ongoing business relationship with you, or otherwise perform our agreement with you.
  * Detect security incidents, protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, or prosecute those responsible for such activities.
  * Debug products to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality.
  * Exercise free speech, ensure the right of another consumer to exercise their free speech rights, or exercise another right provided for by law.
  * Comply with the California Electronic Communications Privacy Act.
  * Enable internal uses that are reasonably aligned with consumer expectations based on your relationship with us.
  * Comply with a legal obligation.
  * Make other internal and lawful uses of that information that are compatible with the context in which you provided it.

To make such a request, please contact us via any of the methods listed in the ‘Contact Us’ section.

**_Verifiable Requests_**

Only you or a person that you authorize to act on your behalf may make a verifiable consumer request related to your personal information. However, you may also make a verifiable consumer request on behalf of your minor (under 16) child.

In order to respond to your requests, we must perform some verification. For example, this would be necessary in order for us to respond to any requests for to disclose or delete your data. Our verification methods will differ depending on the following circumstances:

**Password-protected accounts** – if you have a password-protected account with us, we will use password authentication to verify you. If your request is for deletion of personal information, we will need to re-verify you before we delete your information.

**Non-password-protected accounts** – we need to use either a two-tier or a three-tier verification process (which will depend on what type of request you are making). We will ask for you to confirm two or three pieces of information that we have on our records about you, for example:

  * Your address
  * Your zip code
  * Your most recent purchase
  * Your email address

We will never ask for the following information from you:

  * Social security number
  * Driver’s license number
  * State identification number
  * Medical and health information
  * Financial account number
  * Account passwords
  * Security questions and answers

**_Frequency_**

You may make a verifiable consumer request up to two times within a twelve-month period, without charge. Unfortunately, we cannot respond to your request or provide you with personal information if we cannot verify your identity or authority to make the request and confirm that the personal information relates to you. Making a verifiable consumer request does not require you to create an account with us. We will only use personal information provided in a verifiable consumer request to verify the requestor's identity or authority to make the request.

**_Response Timelines_**

We try to respond to a verifiable consumer request within 45 days of its receipt.  If we require more time, we will inform you of the reason and extension time period (up to 90 days). If you have an account with us, we will deliver our response to that account. If you do not have an account with us, we will deliver our response by mail or electronically, at your option. Any disclosures we provide will only cover the twelve-month period preceding receipt. The response we provide will also explain any reasons we cannot comply with a request, if applicable. 

**_Opting-Out of Sale of Personal Information_**

If you wish to opt–out of the sale of personal information, please use one of the methods in the 'Contact Us' section. If exercised, the decision to opt–out will be valid for 12 months, at which time we may request that you authorize the sale of personal information again.

**_Discrimination_**

We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your CCPA rights. Unless permitted by the CCPA, we will not:

  * Deny you goods or services.
  * Charge you different prices or rates for goods or services, including through discounts or other benefits, or imposing penalties.
  * Provide you a different level or quality of goods or services.
  * Suggest that you may receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services.
